Guide to the Mattie E. Hewitt & Richard A. Smith Photograph Collection 1919-1961 (bulk 1920-1939) PR 26
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Photographic Prints
  - Untermeyer, Samuel (Offsite-box 40, Folder 872)
    "Greystone", Yonkers, NY
  - Vail, Martha C., 1925 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 609)
    116 East 63rd St.
  - Vail, Martha C., 1928 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 610)
    141 East 72nd St.
  - Valentine, 1941 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 611)
    Westport, CT
  - Valentine, Patrick A., Mrs., 1925 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 612)
  - Van Ingen, McLean, Mrs., 1925 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 613)
    903 Park Avenue
  - Van Nort, Anna B. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 873)
    "Four Acres", Yorktown Heights, NY
  - Van Vranken, Frederick, 1937 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 614)
    Sayville, NY
  - Vanderbilt Hotel, 1934-1955 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 615)
    Miscellaneous
  - Vanderbilt Hotel, 1960-1961 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 616)
    the Manger
  - Vanderbilt, William K., Mrs., 1926 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 617)
    "Alva" [yacht]
  - Vanderbilt, William K., Mrs., 1933 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 618)
    60 East 93rd Street
  - Venino, Mrs., 1934 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 619)
    35 West 83rd Street
  - Vernay, Arthur S. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 874)
    Ossining, NY
  - Vesey, Mrs., 1928 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 620)
    400 West 199th Street
  - Victoria Hotel, 1937 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 621)
    Seventh Avenue and 51st Street
    See also: Series II, box 34, folder 727
  - Volkhardt, John M. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 875)
  - Vollmer, David R. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 876)
    Louden Heights, Loudenville, NY
  - Von Glahn, John, 1931 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 622)
    1 Wall Street, office
  - W. & J. Sloane, 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 623)
    Fifth Avenue and 47th Street
  - W. A. Hathaway & Co., 1936 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 624)
    51 West 45th Street
  - W. S. Tyler Co., 1944 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 625)
    See also: Series II, Box 34, folder 728
  - Waldorf Astoria, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 626-628)
    301 Park Avenue
  - Walker, 1927 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 629)
  - Walska, Ganna, 1934 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 630)
    101 East 94th Street
  - Wanamaker (Offsite-box 40, Folder 877)
  - Warburg, Paul, Mrs., 1928 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 631)
    1155 Park Avenue
  - Ward, Reginald (Offsite-box 40, Folder 879)
    Choate Lane, Chappaqua, NY
  - Ward, Stephenson E. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 878)
  - Watson, Dr., 1928 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 632)
    Graybar Building
  - Watts, .H. Mrs. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 880)
  - WCAU Radio Station, 1938 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 633)
    485 Madison Avenue, Room 1501
  - Weiskopf, Daniel K. Mrs. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 881)
    Mamaroneck, NY
  - Weiskopf, James, Mrs., 1933 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 634)
    40 East 88th Street
  - Wellington Hotel, 1940 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 635)
    Seventh Avenue and 55th Street
  - Welsh, Ms., 1929 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 636)
    70 East 77th Street
  - Wentworth Hotel, undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 637)
    59 West 46th Street
  - Westbury Hotel, 1932 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 638)
    15 East 69th Street
  - Westover Hotel, 1935 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 639)
    253 West 72nd Street
  - White Castle Restaurant, 1931 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 640)
    Bronx, NY
  - White, W.A. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 882)
    NY
  - Wickware, M. S., 1926-1928 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 641)
    19 East 47th Street
  - Wigham, R. E., 1925 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 642)
    131 East 65th Street
  - Wightman, M.S., Mrs., 1930 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 643)
    427 Park Avenue
  - Wilder, L.B. Mrs. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 883)
  - Wildman, Frederick, 1941 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 644)
    Colbrook, CT
  - Williams, Harrison, Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 645)
    1130 Fifth Avenue
  - Williams, Nelson B., Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 646)
    31 East 79th Street
  - Willson, Charles M., 1930 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 647)
    Lexington Avenue and 51st Street, Hotel Beverley
  - Willson, Charles M. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 884)
  - Wilson, Francis, Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 648)
  - Windermere Hotel, 1956 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 649)
    West End Avenue and 92nd Street
  - Windmuller, Adolf, Mrs., 1934 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 650)
  - Windsor Hotel, 1949 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 651)
    Sixth Avenue and 58th Street
  - Winslow Hotel, 1949 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 652)
    Madison Avenue and 55th Street
  - Wister, William, Mrs., 1931 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 653)
  - Wivel Restaurant, 1946 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 654)
    254 West 54th Street
    See also: Series II, Box 34, folder 729
  - Wolfe, Nina B., 1941 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 655)
    129 East 62nd Street
  - Wolverton, William H., 1925 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 656)
    510 Park Avenue
  - Women's City Club, 1920 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 657)
    22 Park Avenue
  - Wood, Benjamin, 1926 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 658)
    61 East 52nd Street
  - Wood, John S., Mrs., 1934 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 659)
  - Woodstock Hotel, 1931-1939 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 660)
    127 West 43rd Street
  - Woodward, K.N. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 885)
  - Wyndham Hotel, 1940 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 661)
    42 West 58th Street
  - Yamanaka & Company, 1926 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 662)
    680 Park Avenue
  - York Club, 1922 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 663)
    59 East 56th Street
  - Young, Albert, 1929 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 664)
  - Young House (Offsite-box 40, Folder 886)
  - Zahn, Max, 1934 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 665)
  - Zaiss, Alma, 1940 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 666)
    Hotel Plaza
  - Zeigler, William Jr., 1921 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 667)
    2 East 63rd Street
- Series II: Negatives
  Series II. Negatives consists of 8x10 film negatives made by both Mattie Hewitt and Richard Smith. There are negatives for only a fraction of the prints included in the collection. They are arranged alphabetically by assignment, following the arrangement of the prints. Within each assignment, they are arranged numerically according to the negative number assigned by the photographer.
  - Biddle, Brewster, Brooks, and Bull (Offsite-box 41, Folder 887)
  - Blumenthal, George (Offsite-box 25, Folder 668)
  - Charles of London (Offsite-box 25, Folder 669)
  - Charles Roberson of London (Offsite-box 25, Folder 670)
  - Chesapeake House (Offsite-box 25, Folder 671)
  - Condit, Coulter, and Davie (Offsite-box 41, Folder 888)
  - Cortile Restaurant (Offsite-box 25, Folder 672)
  - Douglas and Espalier (Offsite-box 41, Folder 889)
  - Feigenspan, Edwin, Mrs. (Offsite-box 25, Folder 673)
  - Ferris and Gibson (Offsite-box 41, Folder 890)
  - Gilmore's Restaurant (Offsite-box 25, Folder 674)
  - Grant's Tea Room (Offsite-box 25, Folder 675)
  - Greve (Offsite-box 41, Folder 891)
  - Hammond and Hill (Offsite-box 42, Folder 892)
  - Hampton, Hope (Offsite-box 25, Folder 676-677)
  - Hampton, Hope (Offsite-box 26, Folder 678-680)
  - Harris, Albert (Offsite-box 26, Folder 681)
  - Hearst, William Randolph (Offsite-box 26, Folder 682)
  - Hewitt, Mattie Edwards (Offsite-box 27, Folder 683-684)
  - Hewitt, Mattie Edwards (Offsite-box 27, Folder 685)
    145 West 58th Street, The Meurice
  - Hewitt, Mattie Edwards (Offsite-box 27, Folder 686)
    123 West 57th Street, The Salisbury
  - Hoguet, Dr. J. P. (Offsite-box 27, Folder 687)
  - Hortus Inc. (Offsite-box 27, Folder 688)
  - Hotel Pierre (Offsite-box 28, Folder 689-690)
  - House of Ideas (Offsite-box 28, Folder 691)
  - Huston, Joseph (Offsite-box 28, Folder 692-693)
  - Jaffray, Lehman, Mintz, and Nichols (Offsite-box 42, Folder 893)
  - John Scheepers, Inc. (Offsite-box 29, Folder 694-695)
  - John Scheepers, Inc. (Offsite-box 29, Folder 696-697)
  - Killane, J.L. (Offsite-box 29, Folder 698)
  - Lehman, Arthur, Mrs. (Offsite-box 29, Folder 699)
  - Machine & Tool Designing Co. (Offsite-box 29, Folder 700)
  - Morgan, Anne (Offsite-box 30, Folder 701)
  - Morgan, Anne (Offsite-box 30, Folder 702-705)
  - Nadelman, Elie (Offsite-box 31, Folder 706-708)
  - Old New York Exhibition (Offsite-box 31, Folder 709)
  - Orbach (Offsite-box 42, Folder 894)
  - Porter, Seton (Offsite-box 32, Folder 710-711)
  - Richard E. Thibout, Inc. (Offsite-box 32, Folder 712)
  - Roosevelt Hotel (Offsite-box 32, Folder 713-714)
  - Ross Country Club (Offsite-box 32, Folder 715)
  - Rubicam and Shields (Offsite-box 42, Folder 895)
  - Ruby Foo Restaurant (Offsite-box 33, Folder 716)
  - Sea Cove Restaurant (Offsite-box 33, Folder 717)
  - Shirley, W. T. (Offsite-box 33, Folder 718)
  - Siegel, Annette (Offsite-box 33, Folder 719-721)
  - Skipper, The (Offsite-box 34, Folder 722)
  - Skipper, The (Offsite-box 34, Folder 723)
    59 West 46th Street, Wentworth Hotel
  - Skipper, The (Offsite-box 34, Folder 724)
  - Slides (Offsite-box 42, Folder 900)
  - Sulgrave (Offsite-box 34, Folder 725)
  - Thorne (Offsite-box 42, Folder 896)
  - Town & Country Restaurant (Offsite-box 34, Folder 726)
  - Unter Meyer (Offsite-box 42, Folder 897)
  - Victoria Hotel (Offsite-box 34, Folder 727)
  - W. S. Tyler Co. (Offsite-box 34, Folder 728)
  - Weiskopf (Offsite-box 42, Folder 898)
  - Wivel Restaurant (Offsite-box 34, Folder 729)
  - Poor condition negatives (Offsite-box 42, Folder 899)